<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-08-01T10:33:34+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Xtaycation</title><subtitle>My personal blog. I write about software development, coding exercises, cool tips and tricks and notes for learning &amp; development purposes.</subtitle><author><name>Xuanken Tay</name><email>xuankentay@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Hemis Monastery of Ladakh and the Hemis Festival</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/hemis-monatery-of-ladakh-and-the-hemis-festival/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hemis Monastery of Ladakh and the Hemis Festival" /><published>2022-07-06T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-07-06T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/hemis-monatery-of-ladakh-and-the-hemis-festival</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/hemis-monatery-of-ladakh-and-the-hemis-festival/"><![CDATA[<p>Hemis Monatery of Ladakh is the largest and the richest monastery of the Ladakh region. 45 milometers from Leh, stands this famous gompa or monastery at the Hemis Village, near the Hemis National Park where the endangered snow leopards are found. This 40 kilometres drive is something that remains etched in the memory for a very long time. This 11th century monastery of Drukpa Kagyu lineage (Red Hat Sect of Buddhism) was restored in 1672 AD by Taktsang Respa Ngawang Gyatso under the patronage of the Ladakhi King, Sengge Namgyal. A golden Buddha seated on a hill top overlooks the vast expanse of the valley and the sprawling monastery. This Himalayan Tibetan-Buddhist Monastery, perched at an altitude of 12000 feet is globally famous for the Hemis Festival in June-July. In 2022, i.e.,this year the dates are 8th and 9th of July.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6957.jpg" title="Drive from Hemis to Leh">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6957.jpg" alt="Drive from Hemis to Leh" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6975.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6975.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6959.jpg" title="Hemis">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6959.jpg" alt="Hemis" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6963.jpg" title="Entrance to the Courtyard">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6963.jpg" alt="Entrance to the courtyard" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6976.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6976.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6965.jpg" title="Hemis Gompa">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6965.jpg" alt="Hemis Gompa" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6964.jpg" title="Courtyard">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6964.jpg" alt="Courtyard" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6977.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6977.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6958.jpg" title="Road to Hemis">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfirst/IMG_6958.jpg" alt="Road to Hemis" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="things-to-see-at-hemis-monastery-of-ladakh">Things to See at Hemis Monastery of Ladakh:</h2>

<p>Hemis Monastery of Ladakh has a typical Tibetan architecture where ample use of mud, wood and stones for construction is observed. Walls of the gompa have detailed murals of Tibetan gods and goddesses and other sacred symbols significant to Tibetan Tantric Buddhism. ‘Wheel of Life’ is an important painting. These paintings are extremely colourful and the colourful prayer flags compliment them and there are numerous prayer wheels of various sizes too. The vivid colours look beautiful in contrast to the rugged mountains or landscape around. A large courtyard is at the center and to its right from the entrance is Tshogs-khang, the main temple of the Buddha housing a huge gilded blue haired idol of Sakyamuni Buddha. The Du-Khang, another part of the temple, is the main Assembly Hall with the throne of the Rinpoche and the seats for the lamas (monks). There is temple dedicated to Guru Padmasambhaba and the founder of the Hemis Monastery of Ladakh. The Hemis Museum, the mural gallery and a souvenir shop are must visit sites within the gompa. The museum exhibits items, sculptures, paintings, manuscripts and thangkas which are as old as thousand years. The mural gallery has wall paintings done with stone and natural dyes. Do not miss the roof top because the panoramic view from the terrace is breath taking. Try out Tibetan dishes at the café just outside the monastery; they are delicious. The visiting time is 8 am to 6 pm and 1 pm-2 pm is lunch hour. Ticket cost per person for entry is Rs.50 and it includes a visit to the museum as well.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6969.jpg" title="Staircase to the entrance/courtyard">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6969.jpg" alt="Staircase to the entrance/courtyard" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6968.jpg" title="view from the terrace">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6968.jpg" alt="view from the terrace" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6966.jpg" title="Guru Padmasambhava">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6966.jpg" alt="Guru Padmasambhava" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6970.jpg" title="A Monk with cymbals at the mural gallery">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6970.jpg" alt="A Monk with cymbals at the mural gallery" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6961.jpg" title="Lama's stay">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6961.jpg" alt="Lama's stay" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6967.jpg" title="Terrace">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6967.jpg" alt="Terrace" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6971.jpg" title="Hemis Gompa courtyard">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6971.jpg" alt="Hemis Gompa courtyard" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6972.jpg" title="Prayer wheel">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemissecond/IMG_6972.jpg" alt="Prayer wheel" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="hemis-festival-at-hemis-monastery-of-ladakh">Hemis Festival at Hemis Monastery of Ladakh</h2>

<p>Hemis Monastery of Ladakh boasts of the famous Hemis Festival which takes place in June or July (10th and 11th day of the fifth month of Tibetan Lunar calendar), to commemorate the birth anniversary of Guru Padmasambhava or Rinpoche. The festival is unique and colourful and is celebrated with tremendous devotion and spiritual fervor. The festival begins with rituals are performed by the chief monk in association with other monks. A 350 years old huge (20 feet) thangka with image of Guru Rinpoche is hung from top for the devotees. Mask dances called Chham, performed by the monks at the courtyard make the festival so distinctive and special. The dances mostly imply ‘the holy’ driving away ‘the unholy’. Ritualistic chants, beating of drums, clashing of cymbals and wailing of conchs and Tibetan horn pipes (dughchen-trumpets) create a magical environment of festivity and transcendental energy.</p>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/silk.jpg" title="Thangka of Guru Padmasambhava">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/silk.jpg" alt="Thangka of Guru Padmasambhava" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/Md2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/Md2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/Hemis-Festival_1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/Hemis-Festival_1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/festival.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/festival.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/trumpets-1.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisthird/trumpets-1.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="the-mask-dances-of-hemis-festival">The Mask Dances of Hemis Festival</h2>

<p>The mask dances of Hemis Festival is the chief attraction and follow a sequence with each dance representing a story. The audience at Hemis Monastery of Ladakh is not restricted to Buddhists only. From all across the globe keen visitors come to attend the festival; devotees, travelers, photographers and film makers.</p>

<ul>
  <li>The series of dances begin with the dance of the 4 Gomas or Gatekeepers who wear vibrant brocade dresses and huge wooden masks with skulls on top. Their dance is meant to bind the evil spirits so that they cannot escape.</li>
  <li>Next come the 12 Zhings or Dharmapalas, the guardians of the truth who dance to keep the teachings of the Buddha protected from impurities.</li>
  <li>The dance of the 5 Chemchog Heruka follows next. They represent the fierce form of Guru Rinpoche/ Padmasambhava who eliminates evil with wrath and liberate the land from darkness.</li>
  <li>Then follows the dance of the 4 Lords of the Graveyards who celebrate the death of immorality. They rejoice to celebrate the triumph of good over evil. They wear large wooden masks which look like skulls and their attires also have skeleton woven on them.</li>
  <li>The dance festival ends with the Black Hat Dance by 13 monks. They close the dance with a ritual of protecting the sacred arena such that evil can’t pervade.</li>
</ul>

<figure class="third ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/mask-dance-2.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/mask-dance-2.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/MD.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/MD.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/festival-ladakh.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/festival-ladakh.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/mask-dance.jpg">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfourth/mask-dance.jpg" alt="" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>

<h2 id="takeaways-from-the-hemis-festival-andor-hemis-monastery">Takeaways from the Hemis Festival and/or Hemis Monastery</h2>

<p>The pivotal point across which the majestic Hemis Monastery of Ladakh and the iconic Hemis Festival revolve is the idea of victory of good over evil. Whether we experience the enthusiasm and energy of the festival or the tranquility and solitude of the monastery during other times, we come out a changed person; a person who can retrospect, differentiate and finally choose between what is right and what is wrong. Buddha said, “By oneself, indeed, is evil done; by oneself is one defiled. By oneself is evil left undone; by oneself, indeed, is one purified. Purity and impurity depend on oneself. No one purifies another.”</p>

<figure class=" ">
  
    
      <a href="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfive/IMG_6962-1.jpg" title="Monks Rehearsing for The Hemis Festival Mask Dance">
          <img src="/assets/album/hemis/hemisfive/IMG_6962-1.jpg" alt="Monks Rehearsing for The Hemis Festival Mask Dance" />
      </a>
    
  
  
</figure>]]></content><author><name>Xuanken Tay</name><email>xuankentay@gmail.com</email></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Festival" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to prepare for the 2-hour, online, proctored, performance-based CKA exam.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">N Lexicographic Integers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/exercises/n-lexicographic-integers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="N Lexicographic Integers" /><published>2022-03-13T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-03-13T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/exercises/n-lexicographic-integers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/exercises/n-lexicographic-integers/"><![CDATA[<p>Given an integer <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">n</code>, return first <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">n</code> integers sorted in lexicographic order.</p>

<p><a href="https://binarysearch.com/problems/N-Lexicographic-Integers" target="\_blank">https://binarysearch.com/problems/N-Lexicographic-Integers</a></p>

<h2 id="examples">Examples</h2>

<h3 id="example-1">Example 1</h3>

<p><strong>Input</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>n = <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">12</code></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Output</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>answer = <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">[1, 10, 11, 12, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9]</code></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="solution">Solution</h2>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/yaeba/16da7be5123724fcf6eccc25581cef5a.js?file=N-Lexicographic-Integers.py"></script>]]></content><author><name>Xuanken Tay</name><email>xuankentay@gmail.com</email></author><category term="exercises" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Given an integer n, return first n integers sorted in lexicographic order.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New York City Taxi Trips Analysis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/nyc-taxi-trips-analysis/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New York City Taxi Trips Analysis" /><published>2022-01-30T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-01-30T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/nyc-taxi-trips-analysis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/nyc-taxi-trips-analysis/"><![CDATA[<p>If you are a big fan of R, then this is for you.</p>

<h2 id="overview">Overview</h2>

<p>Using <a href="https://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/">R Markdown</a> and <a href="https://yihui.name/knitr/">knitr</a>, I created 2 open-source notebooks - one for visualization and one for modelling.</p>

<p>Both notebooks were rendered to HTML documents and they contain not only the code to do ETL, plotting and modelling, but the actual report and comments on findings as well.</p>

<p>The reports and findings are completely <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reproducibility#Reproducible_research">reproducible</a> - in that the results are accompanied by the data and code needed to produce them.</p>

<p>You can find the code for notebooks at this <a href="https://github.com/yaeba/nyc_taxi_trips_analysis">repo</a></p>

<h2 id="key-libraries-used">Key libraries used</h2>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://ggplot2.tidyverse.org/">ggplot2</a> - for data visualization</li>
  <li><a href="https://https://www.tidyverse.org/">tidyverse</a> and <a href="https://cran.r-project.org/package=data.table/vignettes/datatable-intro.html">data.table</a>- for manipulating dataframes</li>
  <li><a href="https://docs.h2o.ai/h2o/latest-stable/h2o-docs/faq/r.html">H2O</a> - for modelling purposes</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="report-1-visualization">Report 1: Visualization</h2>

<p>Read the visualization report <a href="https://yaeba.github.io/nyc_taxi_trips_analysis/nyc_taxi_trips_analysis_visualization.html">here</a>.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The aim of this study is to gain an initial insight into the open source taxi and weather datasets for the year 2015 in the New York city. In the notebook, I will be dealing with millions of taxi trips data, performing initial exploratory data analysis on taxi usage and visualizing the relationships with other attributes.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>In summary, I performed an initial analysis on the green taxi data that contains millions of trip records entire in R - in a reproducible manner. With ggplot and tmap, I depicted the relationship between attributes and geospatial visualization onto map of New York City taxi zones, and then attempted to answer a few questions for the study, using the figures and plots produced.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="report-2-modelling">Report 2: Modelling</h2>

<p>Read the modelling report <a href="https://yaeba.github.io/nyc_taxi_trips_analysis/nyc_taxi_fares_analysis.html">here</a></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The aim of this project is to make a qualitative analysis and gain insights into the open source New York City Taxi and Limousine Service Trip Record Data. In the notebook, I will tackle a research problem and perform analysis on millions of taxi trips data.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>In short, I performed an analysis on taxi fares using the green taxi data that spans from year 2014 to 2015 entirely in R - in a reproducible manner. I reported the taxi fare and its relation with other attributes as an attempt to shed light and infer the hypotheses proposed. Then, statistical models were fitted on training set and evaluated using validation set, each of which contains 3 million records each. Models were then compared, interpreted and a final model was chosen after refining the models. Finally, suggestions for further improving the performance were given.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Xuanken Tay</name><email>xuankentay@gmail.com</email></author><category term="projects" /><category term="visualization" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis and modelling on the New York City Taxi Trip data that contains millions of trip records, all in R]]></summary></entry></feed>